<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ebira People</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <!-- onBoarding screen texts -->
    <string name="welcome_text">The Ebiras like all other nationalities in the world have their own
        heroes and heroines. The Ebira speaking people are scattered in four locations in Nigeria.  </string>
    <string name="underline_ebira"><u>Ebira</u></string>
    <string name="underline_people"><u>People</u></string>
    <string name="get_started">Get Started</string>
    <string name="learn_more">Learn More</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="second_onboarding_text">Become a pro in our norms and culture.</string>
    <string name="first_message">Get to know our Royal History.</string>
    <string name="last_onboarding_text">Have a view of amazing places Like the palace of the Ohinoyi of Ebira Land</string>


    <!--Home Fragment-->
    <string name="good_mornig"> Nyene</string>
    <string name="good_afternoon"> Nyari odu</string>
    <string name="good_evening"> Nyari oruva </string>
    <string name="sleeping">You\'re supposed to be sleeping </string>
    <string name="beautiful_places">Beautiful Places</string>
    <string name="hi">Tao</string>
    <string name="search_area_text">Search</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="culture">Culture</string>
    <string name="people">People</string>
    <string name="entertainment">Entertainment</string>

    <!--History Fragment-->
    <string name="history_of_ebira_people">Ane Ebira, we are an ethno-linguistic group in Nigeria. Many of us are from Kogi State, Kwara State, Nasarawa State, Federal Capital Territory, Abuja, and Edo State. Okene is said to be our administrative centre, the Ebira-speaking people in Kogi state, are not far from the Niger-Benue confluence. Origin of the Ebiras An elder beats the Agidibo to salute the spirits (Photo by EbiraView) Ebira Tao is the largest of the several Ebira groups found in about 8 states of Nigeria including the Federal Capital Territory (FCT). Our sister groups are Ebira Koto and Ebira Mozum (Kogi state), Ebira Panda, Ebira Oje/Toto (Nassarawa state), Ebira Etuno (Edo state), Ebira Agatu (Benue state) Ebira Oloko (Ondo/Oyo/Osun states). The history of our origin were those compiled from Attah Omadivi and other Ebiran Clan Heads by the British colonial administrators in early 20th century. Our elders, through oral tradition, trace our descent to Wukari (in the present Taraba state) where we were an integral part of the Kwararafa confederation. In about 1680 AD, our ancestors (along with the Idoma and Igala) migrated out of Wukari over a chieftaincy dispute. Our people later split into various groups and settled in different locations between 1680 and 1750 AD. We Ebira Tao first sojourned with the Igalas at Idah but later crossed the River Niger and settled at Ebira Opete located in the vicinity of Upake in Ajaokuta LGA. Our \'father\' of Ebira Tao who led us to this premier settlement in Ebiraland was Itaazi. Itaazi had five (5) sons who all later migrated from Ebira Opete and were the founders of the various districts in Ebiraland. The children and the districts they founded are Adaviruku/Ohizi (Adavi), Ododo (Okehi), Obaji (Eyika), Uga (Okengwe) and Ochuga/Onotu (Ihima). His daughter named Ohunene settled in Eganyi district. Members of the various clans in Ebiraland are descendants of the children of Itaazi. Ohizi had five children who are progenitors of the five traditional Adavi clans named after them. These are upopo-uvete (Apasi), Uka, Idu (Aniku), Adeyika and Uhwami. A migrant group from Eganyi known as Ezi-Onogu clan is also found in Adavi. The sons of Ododo who are the ancestors of Okehi clans were Okovi Oviri and Enwgukonyai. Obaji the founder of Eika had ten children named Ohiaga, Iyewe, Avassa, Ehemi, Anchi, Epoto, Egiri, Ubobo, Ogu and Eyire. Uga of Okengwe had two sons whose children constitute the present Okovi and Agada group of clans. Due to a sizeable concentration of other Ebira clans in Okengwe district, they formed a socio-political coalition known as Ada-ehi. Ochuga had six children and their descendants make up the six clans in Ihima. These are Emani, Oha/Idu, Ohueta, Ure, Ohongwa and Odumi. The seventh clan is Akuta who migrated from Okengwe. Though Itaazi\'s daughter named Ohunene was the founder of Eganyi, not all the clans there are descended from her. Eganyi clans are Ede, Esugu, Eheda, Ogu, Onoko, Idu, Anavapa and Ogodo. The Aningere who are skilled craftsmen are found in all districts. They are, however, more concentrated in Okengwe and Adavi districts. We constitutes one of the ethnic groups in the Middle Belt zone of Nigeria. But, however, did not evolve a centralized form of leadership until the advent of the British colonial authorities, which brought together the various Ebira clans under the leadership of Attah Omadivi in 1902. therefore, the year 1902 marked the evolution of a monarchical form of administration and the gradual development of central administration in Ebiraland. Location and size of the Ebira community Ebiraland is a small hilly inland area that stretches roughly for twenty three kilometres west of the Niger at Ajaokuta and thirty two kilometers southwest of the Niger-Benue confluence. The range of hills occasionally rises to six hundred and sixty seven metres above sea level. Ebiraland, the home of Ebira Tao, is in the central senatorial District of Kogi state. It has a landmass of 3,426 km2. The 1991 national census puts the population of the area 722,032. Another national head count was undertaken in 2006. The provisional figure of 884,396 released by the National Population Commission (NPC) is being disputed. It is distributed as follows: Okene LGA (320,260), Adavi LGA (202,194), Okehi LGA (199,999), Ajaokuta LGA (122,321) and Ogori Magongo LGA (39,622). Our communities which started as tiny villages have joined together as near towns, gradually and progressively expanding towards one another with Okene as a city in modern times. Ebiraland thus presents an aerial view of one huge near urban settlement with intervening barriers. Our Culture and Administration We are republican by nature, outspoken and very hard working. Farming and cloth-weaving are occupations for which Ebiras are well known. we are presently spread in five Local Government Areas of Kogi state namely: Adavi, Okene, Okehi, Ajaokuta and Ogori-magongo. A sizeable number is of our people are found in Lokoja Local Government Area, Ondo, Ogun, and Oyo states. Our paramount ruler is called Ohinoyi of Ebiraland. The Pre-Colonial Ebira community was essentially segmentary. It consisted of five principal clans among several others, namely, Okengwe, Eika, Okehi, Adavi, and Ihima. The respective priests (heads) of these clans were known as Ohindase, Adeika, Ohiomahi, Asema and Obonbanyi. Each clan was selfgoverning and did not regard any other as superior to it. Significantly, the clan was the main unit of political organization. The post of the clan head was normally conferred on the oldest living male member of the clan. His religious duties and disciplinary powers were, however, limited to his own family. His political influence was quite small and although he presided over the meetings of his clan, his judgement was determined largely by the consensus of opinion of the elders. The administration of all the clan heads constituting a community in Ebiraland lay in the hands of the elders, influential individuals and the chief priest (Ohinoyi). Economically, the clan head held in trust for the clan, part of the income from all the clan lands, such as the produce from palm oil and locust bean trees,during the pre-colonial period. Also, the leg of whatever game that was killed was given to him, which he shared with the kindred heads.We so much cherish our traditional festivities in spite of the infiltration of some negative tendencies in recent times. Our people were used to coming together in the face of crisis. Thus, in moments of war, we come together as a united front to ward off the incursion of the enemy. Indeed, our people have built strong confidence inour warfare and ‘superior’ weapons – bows and arrows. The invasion of Ebira country by the Nupe (1865-1900) did not make them doubt our military superiority. Our Nupe invaders were successfully resisted by our people under our amiable warrior leader who later became Attah Omadivi. The Nupe invasion was organized in the form of raids for slaves. But the our people were soon to realize that our warfare and ‘superior’ weapons could not defend us against the British super superior weaponry in 1902. In 1895, an outstation was placed at Kabba by the Royal Niger Company and a fort was built there by Captain Turner, an officer attached to the Niger Constabulary. On 1st January, 1900, Frederick Lugard took over the government of Northern Nigeria from the Royal Niger Company and hoisted the British flag at Lokoja. Kabba was formed into a province which included the Akoko, Kukuruku and Ebira countries, and was administered from Lokoja, which was also the headquarters of the protectorate of Northern Nigeria, with Sir William Wallace as its first Resident. In 1902, a small military escort led by Mr. Malcom and Lt. F.F.W.Byng-Hall sent into Ebira country was seen by the our people as an incursion. They refused to meet with the British demand for the supply of food, seeing this as a direct insult on their persons. Mr. Malcom and his party, outnumbered, were attacked with arrows by the Ebira and escaped by a night march to Kabba, arriving the next day. The British soldiers used this as casus belli and marched on them with fire arms. The Ebira country was subjugated and pacified. The resident in Ebiraland described the result of the expedition asfollows: “The Ebira were no doubt severely punished during the expedition and I now find them very afraid of the whiteman” With the defeat of our people, the British then imposed their rule on us, politically uniting the various clans by force. During the British occupation of our land, Agidi, one of the notable personalities among the Ebira, led an armed resistance against any form of British rule. In 1902, he and his men attacked the small British group led by Mr. Malcom, the political officer. Who barely escaped death. After this event, Ebiraland was declared a land of ‘savages’ and Mr Malcom ordered a detachment of the West African Frontier Force (WAFF) to sit among our people in order to ‘tame’ them. In 1903, a punitive expedition under Major Marsh, Lieutenants Sparrenbarg, Moran, Byng-Hall, Gallway, Smith, Oldman and Captain Lewis, was organized to call Agidi to order and to establish permanent peace in Ebiraland. In this expedition, the British received the whole hearted cooperation of Omadivi, who was the representative of Ohindase Abogunde – the chief priest at the time. Omadivi, like Ohindase, was from the Okengwe clan. Omadivi supplied vital information, most especially on how to capture Agidi who was his political rival. In fact, both Omadivi and Agidi were notable personalities or influential individuals in the Ebira of that time. While the former was loyal to the Chief priest, the latter was not. By 1904, Ebiraland was fully pacified and Mr. Morgan, the Resident of Kabba province, was able to say with confidence that the Ebira people now feared the ‘‘whiteman” and were at “peace with each other”.</string>

    <!-- People Fragment names and description-->
    <string name="p2">ODODO AND OBAJI</string>
    <string name="p2_d">The Ebiras are said to have descended from these two great ancestors who were said to be brothers. These two great ‘Ohiku Anebira’ are our greatest heroes of our time because they set all the moral standards by which we lived before the coming of Christianity and Islam that approved or confirmed some of the ethics and rules. They also established dos and don’ts and prescribed  the appropriate punishments for the violators/offenders and other deviants in the then</string>
    <string name="p3">OBEGE</string>
    <string name="p3_d">Obege was said to be a great medicine man. He used his magical power to solve people’s problems and did not cause any problem for anybody. He cured all sorts of ailments, made the barren fertile (solving barrenness of couples) and also appeased God on behalf of the people for rains to fall whenever there was unexpected drought in Ebiraland. He attempted to reach God through the long thread contributed by the people and came back through the earth to the ground when the long thread on the ground was exhausted. As a result of the mystery surrounding how his grave opened in the centre of flat rock by itself and closed by itself after burial, Achewuru sang a song, lamenting that if the Ebiras had known, they would have designated his grave yard as a tourist attraction where he believed that some Muslim Pilgrims after visiting Medina would have thought of going there to also pay homage!</string>
    <string name="p4">ZAINAB IYEB</string>
    <string name="p4_d">She was the mother of Attah of Ebiraland. She was a big time business woman who travelled far and wide. She also understood and spoke many languages. She is our first heroine by any standard used, first by giving birth to such a colossus as the Attah of Ebiraland and secondly, by being instrumental in the emergence of her son as the first and only Attah of Ebiraland at the young age of 17years.



        Ohizi (Adaviruku) – Son of Itaazi and founder of Adavi district



        Uga – Son of Itaazi and founder of Okengwe district



        Ochuga – Youngest son of Itaazi and founder of Ihima district



        Ohunene – Daughter of Itaazi and founder of Ihima district



        Obege Ikaturu – Greatest herbalist in Ebira history



        Otase – Greatest marksman in Ebira history



        Atta Omadivi Abonika – Ebira war commander during the 1885 Ajinimo war (Nupe invasion of Ebiraland in which Ebira defeated the Nupe)



        Ovanesi – War commander during the Ebira/Bassa war where the Bassa were defeated (1890).



        Zainab Ejinovo Iyebe – Princess and later ‘Queen mother’ of imense influence



        Onono Idogido – Great social crusader and leader of 1951 women revolt against taxation.</string>
    <string name="p5">ALHAJI ONORUOIZA ARAGARAGA LEREMA IBRAHIM</string>
    <string name="p5_d">He was the first and only Attah of Ebiraland who came to the throne in 1917 and ruled for several decades. His reign witnessed visible developments like roads construction within and outside Ebiraland, construction of Water Works and the building of the Ebira Central Mosque. The Ebira Central Mosque at the time of its construction was second of its kind after Ibadan Central Mosque in Nigeria. He was the first Ebira man to go to</string>
    <string name="p6"> Alh.(Dr.) AbdulRahman Ado Ibrahim (HRH)</string>
    <string name="p6_d">The Ohinoyi Of Ebiraland.
        Born on 7th Feb. 1929.He assumed the office of Ohinoyi of Ebiraland, 2nd June 1997, after the passing away of the former Ohinoyi, Alhaji Sanni Omolori who ruled for 40 years and 40 days as Ohinoyi of Ebiraland.
        Alh.(Dr.) AbdulRahman Ado Ibrahim attended a Nursery and Quranic School and later finished his primary education from NA School in Okene, Kogi State in 1940. He later went to Ondo Boys high School and Oduduwa College and rounding up his secondary education in 1949.
        He obtained a B.Sc in Economics from London School in 1954 and an MBA from Harvard business School, 1959. His enthronement as the Ohinoyi of Ebiraland was a grand occasion, attended by thousands of Ebiras and international diplomats and was broadcast on major Nigerian Television stations for days. He rules Ebiraland from his magnificent pavilion, AZAD Palace named after his son.The palace is rated as one of the most beautiful palaces in west Africa.
        Captivating, majestic, wide and strategically located around Inioziomi area of Okene. This palace\'s minarets shoot high and view able from many high grounds in Okene and neighboring part of ebiraland.</string>
    <string name="p7">ALHAJI SHEHU MUSA GALADIMA</string>
    <string name="p7_d">He was selected as the Chief Imam of Ebira Central Mosque through divine intervention by God when there was a crisis over the position of the chief Imamship of Ebira Central Mosque. Since then, he had never disappointed the Ebiras because peace and unity of the Ebiras have been the hallmarks of his sermons over these decades.
        He is a peacemaker, a bridge builder and a society developer who has left an indelible mark in the history of Ebiraland,
        He died at the age of 98yrs and served as the Chief Imam of Ebiraland for 55yrs</string>
    <string name="p8">SENATOR AT AHMED (December 17, 1941 – June 10, 2006)</string>
    <string name="p8_d">He was a Nigerian politician who was Senator for the Kogi Central constituency in Kogi State from 1999 to 2003 as a member of the People\'s Democratic Party (PDP).
        When Kogi State was created in 1991, Ahmed Tijani Ahmed joined a group of liberal progressive politicians in the Social Democratic Party (SDP) that created an agreement on power sharing among the different peoples of the state. However, they lost the December 1991 governorship election to the National Republican Convention (NRC). Abubakar Audu of the NRC was elected and held office until General Sani Abacha assumed power in November 1993.
        After the return to democracy in 1998, Ahmed Tijani Ahmed aspired to become PDP candidate for the governorship of Kogi State, competing with Steve Achema and others. However, the PDP selected an Okun, Steve Oloruntoba, as a compromise candidate. A.T. Ahmed asked his Ebira supporters to vote for the All People\'s Party governorship candidate, Prince Abubakar Audu, rather than Steve Oloruntoba, which they did. Audu was elected for a second term as governor. Disappointed in his ambition to become governor, A.T. Ahmed ran for a seat in the Senate, which he won, taking office in May 1999. He was appointed head of the senate services committee, which reportedly agreed to share certain contracts among principal officers and committee members.
        He competed with Ibrahim Idris, an Igala, to be chosen as PDP candidate for the 2003 Kogi State governorship election, but was not successful. The PDP leaders decided that the candidate had to be an Igala rather than an Ebira. He was said to have been asked to nominate the deputy governorship candidate, and named Philip Ozovehe Omeiza Salawu. However, later the two men became rivals in the Kogi PDP leadership.

        Ahmed died in a car accident in June 2006.
        May his soul continue to rest in peace (Ameen)</string>

    <string name="p9">Yahaya Adoza Bello</string>
    <string name="p9_d">Bello was born June 18, 1975 in Okene, Kogi State, the youngest of six children. He attended Local Government Education Authority (Nigeria) (LGEA) Primary School, Agassa in Okene LGA beginning in 1984. He was named as a class prefect of class two and was made the school Head Boy in class six
        He attended high school at Agassa Community Secondary School, Anyava, Agassa-Okene and obtained his Junior Secondary School Certificate Examination (JSSCE) and Senior Secondary Certificate Examination (SSCE) certificates from Government Secondary School, Suleja-Niger State in 1994. Bello studied at Kaduna State Polytechnic Zaria in 1995 and obtained an accounting degree from Ahmadu Bello University ABU Zaria in 1999. Yahaya Bello further enrolled for a Masters program in Ahmadu Bello University in Zaria where he obtained Masters in Business Administration (MBA) in 2002. Bello became a chartered fellow of the Association of National Accountants of Nigeria in 2004.
        Bello was declared winner of the 2015 Kogi gubernatorial election after he was chosen on the platform of the All Progressives Congress as the replacement for the late Abubakar Audu who originally won the election but died before the result was declared. On the 16 November 2019, Bello was re-elected after he defeated the PDP opposition by over 200,000 votes.</string>
    <string name="p10">Natasha Hadiza Akpoti</string>
    <string name="p10_d">(born in 1979) is a Nigerian barrister, social entrepreneur and politician. She ran for the post of Kogi Central Senatorial District (SDP) seat under Social Democratic Party in the year 2019. She contested in the Kogi State Governorship election which held on the 16th of November 2019. She is the founder of Builders Hub Impact Investment Program (BHIIP).

        Natasha, the second of four children, and the only daughter of a Nigerian father and a Ukrainian mother. Her mother, Ludmila Kravchenk, is a Ukrainian from Rakitna in the region of Chernivtsi. Her father, Dr. Jimoh Abdul Akpoti, is from Obeiba-Ihima, Kogi State. She spent her early years in Ihima, Okene Local Government She lost her father in 1998 and the family had to relocate. She studied at the University of Abuja from 2000 to 2004 and graduated with a Bachelor of Laws degree. She was called to the Nigerian bar in 2005 upon graduation from the Nigerian Law School in Abuja. In 2011, she proceeded to the University of Dundee and graduated with a Master of Laws degree in 2012. She holds a Master of Business Administration in Oil and Gas Management from the University of Dundee.
        After graduation from the Nigerian Law School, she worked with Brass NLG as a legal counsel from 2007 to 2010. In 2015, she established Builders Hub Impact Investment Program (BHIIP).
        She came to national prominence after presenting an investigative report to the National Assembly on the 1st of March 2018 on corrupt activities regarding the Ajaokuta steel mill. The report detailed the repetitive waste of government funds and embezzlement since the initial construction of the steel mill which has remained moribund despite multiple attempts to get it running. The report was opposed by the Federal ministry of mines and steel development and Akpoti was accused of deliberately misinforming the House of Representatives. An association of small scale steel dealers also alleged that Akpoti was running a sponsored campaign to discredit the government and enrich some corporate interests. A High Court sitting in Abuja ordered that the publisher of Authority newspaper, Ifeanyi Uba and Williams Orji should pay the sum of ten million naira damages to Natasha Akpoti for their libelous publication against her.</string>
    <string name="p11">Alhaji ABDULMALIK ATTA</string>
    <string name="p11_d">The man who brought the letter of independent to Nigeria Alhaji Abdulmalik Atta (1914-1969).
        In 1951, Abdulmalik was nominated by the Native Authority (N.A) to the Northern Regional House of Assembly in Kaduna.
        He pursued a highly pioneering diplomatic career. In the same year, he was also appointed the first Agent General for the Northern Nigeria in the United Kingdom and later became the first Nigerian High Commissioner in the United Kingdom until 1967 when he moved to Paris as the Nigerian Ambassador to France.
        His diplomatic dexterity  was reflected in the remarkable role he played during the trying period for Nigeria\'s Independence. He acted as the vital link between the Colonial Office and Nigerian nationalist leaders through the pre-independence conferences held in London.
        It was in recognition of his excellent diplomatic records
        The Queen of England honored him with the award of the Commander British Empire CBE.
        During the critical period of the political crisis that later led to the Abdication.</string>

    <string name="p12">Nasir Ajanah</string>
    <string name="p12_d">Ajana was born in Okene Local Government Area in Kogi State to MJ Fari Ajanah. Ajana received early education at the Native Authority (Central) Primary School, Okene between 1962 and 1968. In 1969, he enrolled in Federal Government College, Keffi and graduated in 1973. In 1974, Ajana enrolled in the same college for a Higher School Certificate (HSC) finishing in 1975. Ajana earned LLB from Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria. He attended Nigerian Law School and was subsequently called to the Nigerian Bar as a Barrister and Solicitor of the Supreme Court of Nigeria. Ajana\'s legal career started at the Kwara State Ministry of Justice where he served as State Counsel (1982-1984). In 1984, he established his own private firm, Nasiru Ajana and Co in Okene until 1989 when he was appointed a Judge of Kwara State High Court. He was transferred to Kogi State after its creation in 1991.
        Prior to his appointment as Chief Judge of Kogi State, Ajana had served in different capacities. In 1994, Ajana served on the Kabba disturbance tribunal in Kogi State as Chairman. Ajana was Chairman, Election petition tribunal in Adamawa State for the 1998 general elections; Member, Governing board of Nigerian Institute of Advanced Legal Studies (1999-2006); Chairman, Panel on Muritala Mohammed International Airport Fire Incidence (2000); Chairman, Election petition Tribunal in Akwa – Ibom State (2007) and Chairman; Election Tribunal Petition (2) in Rivers State (2008).
        In early 2018, the executive and legislative arm of government in Kogi State commenced a move to remove Ajana from office for an alleged gross misconduct. The State House of Assembly had passed a resolution recommending that the governor remove Ajana from office. Ajana however approached a High Court in Koton Karfe, for an interpretation of the constitution on whether the State House of Assembly and the governor could sack the Chief Judge of the state from office. The court ruled that the Legislature acting jointly with the Executive or unilaterally lacks the powers to remove the Chief Judge of the state without recourse to National Judicial Council (NJC). The Judge in his ruling further stated that "It was an audacious and arbitrary display of naked power, an act that is contrary to all constitutional and democratic tenets.</string>
    <string name="p13">Sheikh Muhammad Amin</string>
    <string name="p13_d">Sheikh Muhammad Amin was born on 6th of April 1963 to the family of late Sheikh Abdullah and Bilkis .
        Sheikh remarkable contribution to the growth and maximum development of Islam as a religion is beyond the pen ink to write.
        He was the first scholar to introduce the teaching of Tajwid(science of Qur\'anic recitation) in ebiraland.
        He was an embodiment of sunnah(following the foot step of our noble Prophet) in all ramifications.

        He reawaken the quest for knowledge in his community and nearby among all preacher\'s, scholars and instructors of Islamic education through his teaching and doing activities.
        As part of his Reformation, the adherent of Terikatul-Tijaniyya of suffi order was/were re-informed about to the people/public/diaspora about the antagonist were curtailed in their preachings activities.
        With Allah\'s permission, Sheikh has reformed the learned students and the public spiritually, socially and otherwise through his periodic preachings lectures.
        His love and caring made people to see themselves as most beloved before him regardless of their belief and status.
        Sheikh is the only scholar in the contemporary time that was not influenced by his followers or been sentimental on any issue either religiously or otherwise.
        He was never confluenced by worldly allotments and allurements because the pleasure of Allah was Paramount on him.
        Sheikh love for the prophet Muhammad (S. A. W) has engraved him and surpassed worldly acquisition.
        Sheikh taught moderation, tolerance, perseverance and brotherhood among Muslims and their communities regardless of their ideological difference.
        Sheikh re-stated the rules and taught on how to purify the soul and how to worship.</string>
    <string name="p14">Oyiza Momoh</string>
    <string name="p14_d">born June 1, 1995) is famous for being TV actress. She currently resides in Glasgow, Scotland, UK. Best known for playing the role of Aneisha Jones in the CBBC television series "M.I. High".
        She has also been a presenter on The Saturday Show.
        Oyiza Momoh was born in Glasgow, Scotland, UK on Thursday, June 1, 1995 (Millennials Generation). She is 24 years old and is a Gemini. She traveled to Kenya to teach life-saving first aid skills. She is a hockey player and began attending Glasgow University in 2015 to study Neuroscience.
        Her family is originally from Nigeria. She has a younger sister named Seyi and her mother’s name is Tola. Oyiza Momoh father’s name is Momoh Jimoh who hailed from #Kogi Central in Nigeria.
        Oyiza Momoh stared in M.I. High, from Series 6-7 (26 episodes). In addition to M.I. High, Momoh has stared in the CBBC television series "The Dog Ate My Homework".</string>
    <string name="p15">Mercy Johnson Okojie</string>
    <string name="p15_d">Mercy Johnson-Okojie hails from Okene in Kogi State. Born in Lagos to a former naval officer, Mr Daniel Johnson and Mrs Elizabeth Johnson, she is the fourth child in a family of seven. She started her primary education in Calabar. Her father, being a naval officer, was later transferred to Lagos State where she continued her education at a Nigerian Navy Primary School. She went to a Rivers State Secondary School for her secondary education in addition to the Nigerian Navy Secondary School in Port Harcourt, Rivers State..

        Right after her secondary education, she auditioned for a role in The Maid and subsequently acted in other movies such as Hustlers, Baby Oku in America, War in the Palace. In 2009, she won an award for Best Supporting Actress at the 2009 African Movie Award ceremony, and Best Actress award at the 2013 Africa Magic Viewers Choice Awards for her role in the comedy movie Dumebi the Dirty Girl. In December 2011, she was listed as Google\'s most searched Nigerian celebrity, a position she also held in 2012. She is the senior special assistant (SSA) to the Kogi state governor on entertainment, arts and culture. This post took effect from 1 April 2017.
        She made her debut as film producer with The Legend of Inikpi.</string>

    <string name="p16">OKINO</string>
    <string name="p16_d">He was a reputable marksman during the invasions of the Ebiras by the combined teams of Jihadists from Bida, Ibadan and Ilorin under the command of Emir Masaba. It is said that he would shoot his arrow up into the air but the arrow would still come down to hit his target. This was how he and other Ebira warriors, hunters, herbalists and other activists used various defence mechanisms to ward off the three times attacks on the Ebiras by the Jihadists.</string>

    <string name="p17">PROFESSSOR Y.O. ALIU</string>
    <string name="p17_d">He is one of the early professors the Ebiras could boast of. He was also one of the most dynamic and colorful National presidents of the Ebira People Association (EPA).</string>

    <string name="p18">PROFESSOR NUHU YAQUB</string>
    <string name="p18_d">He is one of the early professors the Ebiras could boast of. He was two times Vice-Chancellor of Usman Dan Fodio University, Sokoto and one time Vice-Chancellor University of Abuja.</string>
    <string name="p19">ALHAJI MUSA ETUDAIYE</string>
    <string name="p19_d">He used his position as a permanent Secretary in the then Kwara State Civil Service to get some job for qualified Ebira people.</string>
    <string name="p20">RETIRED GENERAL AMUDA ABUBAKAR</string>
    <string name="p20_d">He used his little position when he was in service to enlist some of the young qualified boys into the Nigerian Army</string>

    <string name="p21">DR. ABDULRAHAMAN MUSA ADEIZA</string>
    <string name="p21_d">He is the National President of Ebira People Association for the second time running. He started this national assignment as the President of Ebira People Association, Kano state branch some years ago. Like Prof. Y.O. Aliu, he is a dynamic and colorful national president EPA again is having today.</string>

    <string name="p22">ALHAJI Y. A. IBRAHIM</string>
    <string name="p22_d">He was the first Ebira man to become a Registrar of a University in Nigeria. He was Registrar of Bayero University, Kano for 19 solid years (1975-1995). During this long period of his selfless service to humanity, he helped many Ebira people in admission and work among other people of different extraction.</string>

    <string name="p23">HABIB RAJI ABDALLAH</string>
    <string name="p23_d">He was a Nigerian nationalist who was General Secretary of the Northern Elements Progressive
Association and was president of the Zikist Movement.
He was one of the pioneer nationalists from the Northern
region of Nigeria.

Abdallah was an Ebira and was born in Okene in 1920. His father worked with the colonial authorities as a messenger but later became a judge of the Ebira Native Authority.
Abdallah had the privilege of starting primary school within
the palace of Attah IBRAHIM.
He then attended Bida Middle School and Katsina Training College. In 1936, he began work as an announcer for the Post and Telegraphs department in Lagos, when rediffusion radio service began in Lagos, Abdallah transferred his services to the new department As a radio announcer in Lagos, he became familiar with the nationalist writings of Nnamdi Azikiwe who had just begun publishing his West African Pilot.
In 1940, he was transferred to Kano to work at the Northern region radio rediffusion broadcasting service. His familiarity with Azikiwe\’s writings especially on discrimination emboldened him to create discussions about nationalism in the North, in addition, he joined a few socio-political organizations in the North of like minded individuals such as Osita Agwuna.
In 1946, he co-founded the Northern Elements Progressive Association, an organization with close links to NCNC and he also organized the Kano branch of Zikist Movement, later becoming the association\'s president.
Through NEPA, he sought to raise consciousness about nationalism through public lectures and letters to prominent traditional authorities.
Abdallah\'s role in the Zikist Movement was critical in keeping the group together for a while as ethnic sentiments created division among members.
But a speech by Abdallah then newly appointed president of the movement entitled What is Zikism, emphasizing the group\'s belief in freedom from domination and equality became known to his supervisor who issued him a query for engaging in politics.</string>

    <string name="p24">SAKA RAJI AUDU</string>
    <string name="p24_d">By way of his nickname, he is popularly called hero by his friends and school mates right away from primary up to University level. Today, many people both within and outside the shores of Ebiraland see him as a hero. This is because he has published more than 20 books on variegated topics. He has written articles on pages of national dailies. Some of the publications were part of the books exhibited at the 9th General Conference of Universities that took place on the 13th – 17th January, 1997 at Lusaka, Zambia by the Bayero University, Kano. He is currently the Chief promoter of a monthly Newspaper, Arewa Trust based in Kano.</string>


</resources>